Guide to the Charles Templeman Loram Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1902-1940; Series II
  - Other People's Theses
    - Achterberg, N. D., A Survey of Native Education in the Transvaal, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 224)
    - Christofersen, A. F., The First One Hundred Years of American Board Mission in South Africa, 1835-1936, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 225)
    - Cook, P. A. W., Tribal Education in South East Africa as a Factor in South African Education, undated (Box 11, Folder 226)
    - Hayward, Frederick E., Legislation and Administration Specially Affecting Children and Young People in South Africa, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 227)
    - Heever, Wessel Johannes Van den, Konstitusionele en Staat-Kun dige Studie van die Nuwe Republiek 1884-1888, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 228)
    - Jowitt, Harold, The Reconstruction of Native Education in Southern Rhodesia, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 229)
    - Knott, Harold E., Higher Education in the American Negro, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 230)
    - Long, E. P. M., Report on American Industrial Relations and the Negro, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 231)
    - Matthews, Zachariah Keodirelang, Bantu Law and Western Civilization in South Africa, A Study in the Clash of Cultures, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 232)
    - Perseverando, Bantu Law and Western Civilization in South Africa, A Study in the Clash of Cultures, undated (Box 12, Folder 233)
    - Rao, P. Kodanda, Western and Eastern Civilizations, undated (Box 12, Folder 234)
    - Uys, C. J., Sir Theophilus Shepstone en die Natalse Naturelle Politek van 1846-1876, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 235)
- Government Records, 1885-1923; Series III
  The Government Records in this series are from the South Africa Native Affairs Commission. Included are reports of the Commission to the Minister of Native Affairs, records, laws, and policy statements dealing with the natives and extracts from letters received at the Pensions Office, Pretoria.
  The material is arranged in a sequence of general to particular subject area.
  - South African Native Affairs Commission
    - Native Law, 1885-1923 (Box 14, Folder 236)
    - Natal Code of Native Law and Draft of Suggested Amendments, 1891-1928 (Box 14, Folder 237)
    - The Policy of the British Government Towards the Tribal Natives in South Africa between 1830-1845, undated (Box 14, Folder 238)
    - Records Concerning the Ebenezer Hottentots, 1906-1923 (Box 14, Folder 239)
    - Report on the Native Disturbances at Port Elizabeth, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 240)
    - Report on the Bondelzwart Rising, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 241)
    - Report on the Bondelzwart Rising (3 incomplete copies), 1922 (Box 14, Folder 242)
    - Report on the Bondelzwart Rising (2 copies of a different draft), 1922 (Box 14, Folder 243)
    - Incomplete Report on the Angola-Ovamboland Boundary Commission, undated (Box 14, Folder 244)
    - Proposed Policy with Regard to Native Education, undated (Box 14, Folder 245)
    - Native Churches Inquiry, 1922-1923 (Box 14, Folder 246)
    - Extracts from Letters Received at the Pensions Office, Pretoria, undated (Box 14, Folder 247)
- Miscellaneous, 1779-1813, 1884, 1907, 1934; Series IV
  This series includes photostats, a diary of Thomas Hargreaves on annexation of Pondoland, notes, material from the report of the Senate Investigation committee on South Africa Native Affairs, and several items of printed material.
  - Photostats of various records, 1779-1813 (Box 15, Folder 248)
  - Diary of Mr. Thomas Hargreaves concerning the annexation of Pondoland, 1884 (Box 15, Folder 249)
  - Notes on MacMillan's Bantu, Boer, and Britain, undated (Box 15, Folder 250)
  - Documentary material from the Report of the Senate Investigating Committee, undated (Box 15, Folder 251)
  - St. Joseph's Cathedral, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada Yearbook, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 252)
  - The Spectator, 2 pages, 1907 June 8 (Box 15, Folder 253)
  - "Dillo", typescript of a story by an unidentified author, undated (Box 15, Folder 254)
- Maps, 1922; Series V
  This series contains three maps of South Africa concerned with the South African Native Affairs Commission.
  - Map of the Orange River Mouth in Southwest Africa, undated (Box 16, Folder 255)
  - Map of the border line of the Bondels territory in Southwest Africa, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 256)
  - Map of the Border Commission for the farms of the Bondels, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 257)
- Pictures, 1936, undated; Series VI
  Pictures concern South Africa. Included are two drawings of wild life by Harold M. Millar and two reproductions of native art.
  Photographs of Charles T. Loram among members of the Yale Association of Japan.
  - Picture of the Purple-crested Lourie of Natal by Harold M. Millar, undated (Box 17, Folder 258)
  - Picture of the Black Heron by Harold M. Millar, undated (Box 17, Folder 259)
  - Two reproductions of native art, undated (Box 17, Folder 260)
  - One photograph, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 261)
- Additional material, 1903-1975, undated; Accession 1996-M-085
  - Biographical material, 1903-1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1930-1934, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Mostly incoming, 1915-1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Congratulations on appointment as a Commissioner on Native Affairs, South Africa, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Imperial District Court, [1907?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Phelps-Stokes Fund Dinner [guest list and menu], 1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 1927, 1932, 1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)